Joseph Knox

| 650.709.7272 | joseph.edward.knox@gmail.com | Github: jknox13 | LinkedIn: Joseph Knox

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

M.S. IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS June 2018 | Seattle, WA

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

B.S. IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING Minor in Applied Mathematics June 2016 | Seattle, WA

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Advanced: Python

Intermediate: R • C • SQL • MATLAB C++ • Java • OpenMP/MPI Novice:

Bash/sh

PROJECTS

MCMODELS | MAINTAINER

Dec 2017 - | Python Python library for mesoscopic full-brain connectivity models in mouse.

RISTRETTO | PRIMARY CONTRIBUTOR

April 2018 - | Python

Randomized matrix factorization library written in Python.

CONTRIBUTER TO

- Allensdk
- Scikit-learn

COURSEWORK

GRADUATE

Statistical Computing Combinatorial Optimization Computational Neuroscience Statistical Analysis of Social Networks Computational Methods for Data **Analysis**

UNDERGRADUATE

Machine Learning Stochastic Modeling/Decision Analysis Linear and Network Programming High-Performance Scientific Computing

SUMMARY

A Bachelor of Industrial Engineering and a Master of Applied Mathematics with 1+ years researching statistical, graph theoretic models of brain connectivity. Throughout my diverse work experience I have to identified, communicated, and solved various levels of problems through research, engineering, and with close collaboration with my teamates. I am a driven learner who thrives working with equally driven groups of researchers, engineers, and business-focused professionals. My goal is to use my applied problem solving abilities to impact the core business of the company I work for, and have fun learning in the process.

EXPERIENCE

FACEBOOK

Sept 2018 - Present · 1 yr 6 mos

- Retention
- Product
- Build internal tools
- Complex data pipelines
- A/B testing experimentation

ALLEN INSTITUTE FOR BRAIN SCIENCE

DATA ANALYST

Seattle, WA

DATA SCIENTIST

San Francisco, CA

June 2017 - Sept 2018 · 1 yr 4 mos

- Develop and implement novel models for full-brain connectivity
- Analyze heterogeneous, multi-scale experimental data
- Contribute to organizational open source software packages

RATLAB LLC

RESEARCH INTERN

July 2016 - Jan 2017 · 7 mos Seattle, WA

- Designed and conducted experiments for product research and development
- Optimized hardware design through the use of statistical machine learning techniques

COLLEGE WORKS PAINTING

MANAGER

Feb 2015 - Sept 2015 · 8 mos

Seattle, WA

- Acted as project manager creating estimates and invoices for management of monetary funds
- Planned production schedule and successfully coordinated all projects, interacting with clients daily and ensured customer satisfaction
- Recruited, hired, and trained 3 employees

SELECT PUBLICATIONS

- [1] J. A. Harris and S. e. a. Mihalas. Hierarchical organization of cortical and thalamic connectivity. Nature, 575(7781):195-202, 2019.
- [2] J. E. Knox and K. D. e. a. Harris. High-resolution data-driven model of the mouse connectome. Network Neuroscience, 3(1):217-236, 2019.
- [3] J. D. e. a. Whitesell. Whole brain imaging reveals distinct spatial patterns of amyloid beta deposition in three mouse models of alzheimer's disease. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 527(13):2122-2145, 2019.